Guide to the Glenway Wescott Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1921-84; Series III; 30.87; (74 boxes)
  - GENERAL WRITINGS
    - Goodbye Wisconsin [book]
      - Goodbye Wisconsin [story]
        - Printed version, photocopy, 1928 (Box 264, Folder 2585)
      - Adolescence
        - Draft [copied], typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 264, Folder 2586)
      - A Guilty Woman
        - Printed version, Century, 1928 Aug (Box 264, Folder 2587)
      - The Dove Came Down
        - Draft [copied], typescript, n.d. (Box 264, Folder 2588)
        - Printed version, Harper's Magazine, 1928 Apr (Box 264, Folder 2589)
      - Like a Lover
        - French translation [as "Les Destinées], printed version, La revue européenne, 1928 Mai (Box 264, Folder 2590)
        - German translation [as "Dunkle Mächte"], printed version Neue Schweizer Rundschau, 1928 Aug (Box 265, Folder 2591)
      - In a Thicket
        - Printed version, The Dial, 1924 Jun (Box 265, Folder 2592)
        - French translation [as "Dans un Fourre"], printed version, La revue européenne, 1926 Jan 1 (Box 265, Folder 2593)
          Also includes: "Le portrait de
          Glenway Wescott" by Bernard Faÿ
      - The Sailor
        - Draft [copied], typescript and carbon (Box 265, Folder 2594)
        - Printed version, photocopy, 1955 (Box 265, Folder 2595)
      - The Whistling Swan
        - Printed version, The Bookman, 1928 Jun (Box 265, Folder 2596)
    - The Grandmothers
      - Promotional statements, n.d. (Box 265, Folder 2597)
      - Publicity and announcements, 1927 (Box 265, Folder 2598)
      - Copies of inscriptions in printed versions by GW, 1927, n.d. (Box 265, Folder 2599)
      - "Notes for my preface to the Gr.", draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 265, Folder 2600)
      - Book cover for Atheneum edition, n.d. (Box 265, Folder 2601)
      - Poster for reading [New Jersey], n.d. (Box 265, Folder 2602)
      - Advertisement for direct mail edition, n.d. (Box 265, Folder 2603)
      - Clippings, 1927-86 (Box 265, Folder 2604-2605)
      - "Uncle and Nephew" section [copied], typescript carbon (Box 265, Folder 2606)
      - "Sister of Hunters" section, printed version, The Dial, 1926 Mar (Box 265, Folder 2607)
    - Hurt Feelings
      See also: The Dream of Mrs. Cleveland, Boxes 261-262, folders 2523-2551
      - Drafts, holograph and typescript carbon, corrected, 1929-31 (Box 265, Folder 2608-2611)
      - Drafts [copied], typescript and carbon (Box 266, Folder 2612)
      - Printed version North American Review, 1932 Sep (Box 266, Folder 2613)
    - Images of Truth
      - Draft pages, holograph, typescript, and carbon, corrected, 1962 (Box 266, Folder 2614-2615)
      - Book jacket, 1962 (Box 266, Folder 2616)
      - Publicity material, 1962 (Box 266, Folder 2617)
      - Promotional and tour material, 1962 (Box 266, Folder 2618)
      - Clippings, 1962 (Box 266, Folder 2619-2621)
    - In Praise of Puppets
      - Draft, typescript, 1921 (Box 267, Folder 2622)
    - Italics: Retrospect
      - Draft, typescript corrected, photocopy, ca. 1937 (Box 267, Folder 2623)
    - Jenny Holbrook
      - Draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 267, Folder 2624)
    - Letter to the editor of Time Magazine, 1936 May 30
      - Printed version, Blast at Ballet, 1938 (Box 267, Folder 2625)
    - Letter to the editor [of unidentified publication]
      - Printed version, 1964 Sep 24 (Box 267, Folder 2626)
    - "A Letter to out-of-town critics"
      - Drafts, holograph and typescript carbon
    - The Little Ocean Liner
      - Notebook, 1949 (Box 267, Folder 2627)
      - Section drafts, holograph, typescript, and carbon, corrected, 1943-50 (Box 267, Folder 2628-2642)
      - Section drafts, holograph, typescript, and carbon, corrected, 1943-50 (Box 268, Folder 2643-2645)
      - "The Refugee" section drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected, 1943 (Box 268, Folder 2646)
      - Loose draft pages, holograph and typescript, corrected, 1949-50 (Box 268, Folder 2647)
    - Long Island
      - Drafts, typescript and carbon, corrected, 1938 Aug (Box 268, Folder 2648-2649)
        See also: Various works: 1938 Set Pieces, Box 284, folder 2811
    - The Love of New York
      - Drafts, holograph, typescript and carbon, corrected, 1943 (Box 268, Folder 2650)
        Includes: title pages for other
        manuscripts
      - Printed version [as "I Love New York"], Harper's Bazaar, 1943 Dec
    - Memories and Opinions
      - Notebook, ca. 1972 (Box 268, Folder 2651)
      - Printed version, Prose, photocopy, 1972 (Box 268, Folder 2652)
    - Memories of the Twenties
      - Notebook, ca. 1949-60 (Box 268, Folder 2653)
      - Drafts, typescript and carbon, corrected (Box 269, Folder 2654)
      - Draft pages, holograph, corrected, 1960 Jan (Box 269, Folder 2655)
    - Memory as Criticism
      - Draft fragment, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 269, Folder 2656)
    - Men Like Birds
      - Draft, typescript, 1923 (Box 269, Folder 2657)
    - Mr. Auerbach in Paris
      - Draft sections, typescript and carbon, corrected, ca. 1942 (Box 269, Folder 2658-2659)
      - Printed version, Harper's Magazine, 1942 Apr (Box 269, Folder 2660)
    - The Mouse
      - Notes, ca. 1953-57 (Box 269, Folder 2661)
        Includes: letter from Katharine Dudley
        to GW and letter from GW to William
        Christian Miller
    - The Mumps and Censorship
      - Draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 269, Folder 2662)
    - The Mystery of Mrs. Simpson
      - Draft pages, holograph and typescript, corrected, 1936 Dec (Box 269, Folder 2663)
    - Mythology
      See also: Writings about People:
      - Lynes, George Platt - Illustrations of Mythology, Box 299, folder 2951-2954
      - Notebooks with drafts, typescript, corrected, with photocopies, 1938-59 (Box 269, Folder 2664-2665)
      - Drafts of myths, typescript and photocopy, corrected (Box 269, Folder 2666)
      - Draft fragments, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 269, Folder 2667)
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 269, Folder 2668)
      - "List of photographable myths for GPL", 1938 (Box 269, Folder 2669)
      - "Eros Ephebe" draft [copied], holograph, corrected, 1960 Jan (Box 269, Folder 2670)
    - A Naked Man
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 270, Folder 2671)
    - Natives of Rock
      - Errata notes, n.d. (Box 270, Folder 2672)
      - Clippings, 1926 May (Box 270, Folder 2673)
    - New Year's 1939
      - Draft fragments, typescript carbon, corrected, 1939 (Box 270, Folder 2674)
    - Nocturne in Chicago
      - Draft pages, holograph, corrected, 1947-48 (Box 270, Folder 2675)
    - Notes on Women for Radio
      - Draft pages, holograph, n.d. (Box 270, Folder 2676)
    - The Odor of Rosemary
      - [General Work]
        - Notebooks, ca. 1954-71 (Box 270, Folder 2677-2681)
        - Notebooks, ca. 1954-71 (Box 271, Folder 2682-2686)
        - Notebooks, ca. 1954-71 (Box 272, Folder 2687-2688a)
        - Loose pages, ca. 1939-71 (Box 272, Folder 2689-2691)
        - Loose pages, ca. 1939-71 (Box 273, Folder 2692-2695)
      - Section: That's for Remembrance
        - Draft pages, typescript, carbon, and photocopy, ca. 1968-71 (Box 273, Folder 2696)
        - Galley proof, corrected, [1971] (Box 273, Folder 2697)
        - Printed version, Prose, 1971 (Box 273, Folder 2698)
      - Section: The Emperor Concerto
        - Draft pages, holograph, typescript, carbon, and photocopy, corrected, ca. 1971 (Box 273, Folder 2699-2700)
      - Section: The Breath of Bulls
        - Drafts, holograph, typescript, carbon, and photocopy, corrected, 1970 (Box 273, Folder 2701)
        - Drafts, holograph, typescript, carbon, and photocopy, corrected, 1970 (Box 274, Folder 2702)
        - Galley proof pages, photocopy, corrected, ca. 1972 (Box 274, Folder 2703)
        - Printed pages, photocopied [from "Works in Progress"], 1972 (Box 274, Folder 2704)
      - Section: The Valley Submerged
        - Draft pages, holograph and typescript carbon, corrected (Box 274, Folder 2705)
        - Drafts [for The Southern Review, holograph, typescript and carbon, corrected, 1965 May (Box 274, Folder 2706-2707)
        - Printed version, The Southern Review, 1965 (Box 274, Folder 2708-2709)
          Includes annotated copies
        - Drafts, "retouched version" and variant, holograph and photocopy, 1977-78 (Box 274, Folder 2710)
        - Draft fragment pages, n.d. (Box 274, Folder 2711)
    - The Old Secretiveness
      - Draft, typescript and carbon (Box 274, Folder 2712)
    - One Night in Florida
      - Draft, typescript corrected [photocopy], n.d. (Box 274, Folder 2713)
        Also titled: The Beloved: Night in Florida
    - One Peaceful Week in Morocco
      - Notebook, ca. 1941-65 (Box 275, Folder 2714)
    - The Phenomenal Popularity of Modern Art
      - Notebook, ca. 1939-63 (Box 275, Folder 2715-2716)
    - A Picture of Country Life
      - Drafts, holograph, typescript and carbon, corrected, 1947 (Box 275, Folder 2717-2720)
      - Printed version [as "A Day in the Country"], Tomorrow, 1947 Jul (Box 275, Folder 2721)
    - The Pilgrim Hawk
      - Printed version, photocopy [incomplete], n.d. (Box 276, Folder 2722)
      - Draft of blurb by Paul Horgan, 1940 Dec 7 (Box 276, Folder 2723)
      - Fan letters, 1940-41 (Box 276, Folder 2724)
        Includes: H. S. Wittner
      - Review by Mark Schorer, printed version [ Kenyon Review, 1941 Summer], with draft of response by GW, 1941-50 (Box 276, Folder 2725)
      - "My Hawk Explained", galley proof, annotated, with notes, 1956-57 (Box 276, Folder 2726-2727)
      - GW's envelope for Six Great Modern Short Novels [content removed], n.d. (Box 276, Folder 2728)
      - Alcohol by Berton Roueché, containing citation of The Pilgrim Hawk, 1962 (Box 276, Folder 2729)
      - Publication announcements, 1966 edition (Box 276, Folder 2730)
      - Explanatory letter added to copy of books donated for auction, 1976 (Box 276, Folder 2731)
      - Proof pages from various, unidentified editions, n.d. (Box 276, Folder 2732)
      - Clippings, 1940-67 (Box 276, Folder 2733-2739)
      - Clippings, 1940-67 (Box 277, Folder 2740-2741)
    - Poor Greuze
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, with photocopy, ca. 1935 (Box 277, Folder 2742)
      - Draft [copied], typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 277, Folder 2743)
      - Printed version, Wadsworth Athenuem Report, 1935 June (Box 277, Folder 2744)
    - Priapus in Maine
      See: A Visit to Priapus, Box 279,
      - folders 2779-2780
    - A Quarrel
      See: The Summer Ending, Box 278,
      - folder 2764
    - Remarks at the Clinton Farms Soft-ball Banquet
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, 1957 Oct 14 (Box 277, Folder 2745)
        Includes copy of "The Author's Handbook" given to GW
    - The Rescuer
      - Draft [copied], typescript and carbon (Box 277, Folder 2746)
    - Sacre de Printemps
      - Draft pages, typescript and carbon, corrected, ca. 1923 (Box 277, Folder 2747)
    - The Sight of a Dead Body
      - Draft, typescript carbon, corrected and annotated (Box 277, Folder 2748)
      - Draft pages, typescript and carbon, corrected (Box 277, Folder 2749)
      - Printed version, Signatures, corrected, 1936 (Box 277, Folder 2750)
    - A Simplification of Modern Art
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 277, Folder 2751)
    - Sketchbook for Pauline de R.
      - Draft pages, holograph, typescript and photocopy, 1968-69 (Box 277, Folder 2752)
    - Sounds of Love
      - Draft, holograph, corrected, 1967 Sep 6 (Box 277, Folder 2753)
    - The Soutine-Faced Sailor
      - Draft pages, holograph, 1956 Jul 12 (Box 277, Folder 2754)
    - The Spanish Accident
      - Journal pages, holograph and typescript, 1943, n.d. (Box 277, Folder 2755)
        Includes: other titled sections:
        "We'll be Girls in the Spring", "The
        Misses Ravenal Smith of Charleston",
        and "The Girl Journalist"
    - The Spider and the Mayfly
      - Draft pages, holograph, 1957 (Box 277, Folder 2756)
    - The Stallions
      - Notebooks: "Horses and Humans", ca. 1937-70 (Box 278, Folder 2757-2758)
      - Draft pages, holograph and typescript carbon, corrected, ca. 1937-52 (Box 278, Folder 2759-2760)
    - Still-hunt
      - Draft [copied], typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 278, Folder 2761)
      - Printed version, Poetry, 1921 Sep (Box 278, Folder 2762)
    - Summer Conversations
      - Draft [copied], typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 278, Folder 2763)
    - The Summer Ending
      - Drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected, 1937-55 (Box 278, Folder 2764)
        Includes: Notebook with draft of
        Alwyn Tower's Summer Poem and
        letter to "Miss Davenport"
      - Printed version, Poetry, 1939 Sep (Box 279, Folder 2765)
      - Printed version [as "A Quarrel"], A Just God, 1984 Aug (Box 279, Folder 2766)
    - The Swamp Garden
      See: Various works: 1938 Set Pieces, Box 284, folder 2811
      - Box 284, folder 2811
    - This Quarter's Books: New York
      - Printed version, Transatlantic Review, 1924 Nov (Box 279, Folder 2767)
    - This Way Out [The Runaways]
      - Printed version, Collier's
    - Tommy & St. Thomas
      - Draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 279, Folder 2768)
    - A Transatlantic Glance
      - Draft sections, holograph, typescript and carbon, corrected (Box 279, Folder 2769-2773)
    - 12 Fables of Aesop
      - Draft [copied], typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 279, Folder 2774)
      - Dummy book, n.d. (Box 279, Folder 2775)
      - Order form for printed book version, n.d. (Box 279, Folder 2776)
    - "Unpublished contribution to a newspaper symposium"
      [re: France]
      - Draft, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 279, Folder 2777)
    - Venus on the Shore
      - Drafts [copied], typescript and carbon [with photocopies], annotated (Box 279, Folder 2778)
    - A Visit to Priapus
      - Notebook, 1938 (Box 279, Folder 2779)
      - Draft sections, typescript carbon [photocopy], 1938 (Box 279, Folder 2780)
    - A Visit to Priapus in Oregon
      - Notes, 1976 (Box 279, Folder 2781)
    - Walt, Farewell
      - Notebook, 1948-59 (Box 280, Folder 2782)
    - A War Bond Message from Glenway Wescott
      - Printed version, New York Herald Tribune, 1945 May 14 (Box 280, Folder 2783)
    - Warning from a Novelist
      - Printed version, The Bulletin of the American Veterans Committee, 1945 May 1 (Box 280, Folder 2784)
    - The Weedy Books [Letter to the Editor]
      - Printed version, [ New York Times Book Review ?], n.d. (Box 280, Folder 2785)
    - What Mr. Mumford said about Mrs. Lupu
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 280, Folder 2786)
    - Where and When
      - Drafts, typescript carbon, corrected, 1940 Dec (Box 280, Folder 2787)
    - A Windfall
      - Table of contents drafts, holograph and typescript carbon (Box 280, Folder 2788)
      - Notebooks, ca. 1920-59 (Box 280, Folder 2789-2790)
      - Notebooks, ca. 1920-59 (Box 281, Folder 2791-2792)
      - Notes, 1959 (Box 281, Folder 2793)
      - Drafts [copied], typescript and carbon (Box 281, Folder 2794)
    - Writer's War Board statements
      - Drafts, typescript, carbon, and mimeograph, corrected, 1945, n.d. (Box 281, Folder 2795)
    - A Year of Love
      [excerpts from letters and writings]
      - Notes, 1953 (Box 281, Folder 2796)
      - Loose pages, typescript and carbon, 1938-53 (Box 282, Folder 2797-2803)
    - Young People in Chicago
      - Draft pages, holograph and typescript, corrected [photocopies], ca. 1946-48 (Box 282, Folder 2804)
    - Various works
      - "Criticism" notebook, ca. 1959-70 (Box 282, Folder 2805)
      - "The Discouragement about the Novel" notebook, ca. 1949-56 (Box 283, Folder 2806)
        See also: Lectures, Box 322, folder 3144
      - "Epigraphs" notebook, n.d. (Box 283, Folder 2807)
        Includes: Annotated copy of The Valley
        Submerged
      - Excerpts from reviews of GW's work, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 283, Folder 2808)
      - "Foolish exercises in my urge to get to be a writer", loose pages, holograph and typescript, ca. 1924-26 (Box 283, Folder 2809)
      - "Little Stories" notebook, ca. 1956-57 (Box 283, Folder 2810)
      - "1938 Set Pieces" notebook, ca. 1938 (Box 284, Folder 2811)
        Includes: "An Example of Suicide",
        "Long Island" and "The Swamp Garden"
      - "Out-of-date literary agenda" notebook, 1943-44 (Box 284, Folder 2812)
      - Review of "Classic in English" [various titles] draft [copied], typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 284, Folder 2813)
      - [Scrapbook of early published works], ca. 1922-41 (Box 284, Folder 2814)
      - "Various Stories" notebook, ca. 1949-58 (Box 285, Folder 2815)
        Names of notebook sections:
        Stories
        Great acting
        Barber
        The Requiem
        Story Sequences
        Bunches of Grapes
        The Self-Induced Sores
        The Epileptic's Pills
      - [Untitled notebook of essays on modernist writers], n.d. (Box 285, Folder 2816-2818)
        Cunningham Graham's Letter
        The Mumps and Censorship
        Ford in the Country
        Paris of the Lost Generation
        The Pride of Gertrude Stein
        Hemingway's Contempt
        Joyce and the Ex-Priest
        L'Envoi
        Incorrigeability
        Typicality
        Education
        The Phantom Wedding Ring
        The Importance of Magazines
        Young Snobbishness
        Oscar Williams on the Doorstep
    - Fragments
      - [re: Jean Cocteau, Jean Bourgoint, and life in France during 1920s, draft pages and annotated sections from printed book]
      - "Draft of an American Tribute", holograph and typescript, [1930] (Box 286, Folder 2819)
      - [re: Anthology of short French novels], notes for introduction, holograph and typescript, 1946 (Box 286, Folder 2820)
      - [re: French literature], notebook pages, n.d. (Box 286, Folder 2821)
      - "Miniatures of historical persons", notes, n.d. (Box 286, Folder 2822)
      - "Nina's lament - follow upon Sartre quotation", holograph, n.d. (Box 286, Folder 2822a)
      - [Notecards re: Alwyn Tower, possibly "Children of this World"], n.d.
      - [Notecards re: Alwyn Tower, possibly "Children of this World"], n.d.
      - [Notes for a textbook on writing], 1948 (Box 286, Folder 2823)
      - [Notes on artists], n.d.
      - [Notes on "A. T. as poet" (Alwyn Tower?)], 1939-51 (Box 286, Folder 2824)
      - [Notes re: "Cain and Abel"] (Box 286, Folder 2825)
      - [Notes on chronology of life events], n.d. (Box 286, Folder 2826)
      - [Notes on contemporary poets, including "L. K." (Lincoln Kirstein?)], 1946 (Box 286, Folder 2827)
      - [Notes on MW and and exhibition during wartime]
      - [Poem: "Does the Sea then prance like horses..."], draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 286, Folder 2828)
      - [Story re: Aaron Smart], draft pages, typescript and carbon (Box 286, Folder 2829)
      - [Story re: Uncle Jimmie], draft pages, holograph, n.d. (Box 286, Folder 2830)
      - [re: Writers and publishing], draft pages, holograph (Box 286, Folder 2831)
      - Unidentified draft pages, n.d. (Box 286, Folder 2832)
  - WRITINGS ABOUT PEOPLE
    - Atkins, Roy
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 287, Folder 2833)
        Includes photograph of RA with Henri
        Wessels, June 1933
    - Auden, W. H.
      - Notes, draft of letter by GW and clippings, ca. 1937-75 (Box 287, Folder 2834)
    - Bachardy, Don
      - "Posing for Don", draft, holograph, typescript carbon, and printed version, ca. 1974 (Box 287, Folder 2835)
    - Balanchine, George
      "The Choreographer"
      - Drafts, holograph typescript and carbon, corrected, 1963
      - Notebook, 1963
      - Printed version, Show, 1963 Dec (Box 287, Folder 2837)
        See also: Hotchkiss, Dorothy, "In Memoriam Dorothy Hotchkiss", Box 298, folder 2939
      - "Orfeo and Eurydice" notebook, ca. 1936 (Box 287, Folder 2838)
        Includes draft of letter by GW to Time magazine
    - Bliss, Lillie P.
      - "Mrs. Lillie P. Bliss", draft pages, holograph and photocopy, corrected (Box 287, Folder 2839)
    - Bogan, Louise
      - Copies of Bogan essays from the New Yorker with letter from [Barbara Wescott?], n.d.
      - "Louise Bogan's Last Words" notebook with drafts, clipping and copies of letters, ca. 1933-70 (Box 287, Folder 2840)
    - Bonnard, Pierre
      - "Bonnard Personally" draft pages, holograph, typescript and carbon, corrected, 1964, n.d. (Box 288, Folder 2841)
    - Bowen, Elizabeth
      "Love of a Traitor", review of The Heat of the Day
      - Drafts, holograph and typescript carbon, corrected, 1949
      - Printed version, Saturday Review of Literature, 1949 Feb 19 (Box 288, Folder 2844)
    - Brooks, Van Wyck
      See: Hotchkiss, Dorothy, "In Memoriam Dorothy Hotchkiss", Box 298, folder 2939
    - Browning, Robert and Elizabeth Barrett
      - Notes, 1970 Aug 16 (Box 288, Folder 2845)
    - Butts, Mary and William Plomer
      - Notebook, ca. 1958-83 (Box 288, Folder 2846)
        Includes letters to GW from Robert
        Byington and letter from GW to RB
    - Cheever, John
      - "A Surpassing Sequel", review of The Wapshot Scandal, printed version, Book Week, 1964 Jan 5
    - Clark, Eleanor
      "All of us on the half-shell", review
      of The Oysters of Locmariaquer
      - Drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected, ca. 1964
      - Printed version, Book Week, 1964 Jul 12 (Box 288, Folder 2848)
    - Cocteau, Jean
      - Lecture draft pages, holograph, 1950 (Box 288, Folder 2849)
    - Colette
      "A Call on Colette"
      - Drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected, 1952 Nov
      - Printed version [as "Happy Birthday, Dear Colette"], Town and Country, 1953 Jan (Box 288, Folder 2851)
      - "Colette's Theory of Love", notebook, n.d. (Box 289, Folder 2852)
      - "Introduction to Colette"
        - Drafts, typescript and carbon, corrected, 1951 (Box 289, Folder 2853-2857)
          Includes: letter to Helen Strauss
          from GW and letter from Philip Rahv
        - Abridgement: "A Little Portrait of Colette, draft, typescript, 1951 (Box 289, Folder 2858)
        - Abridgement: "A Little Portrait of Colette, printed version [as "Colette"], Vogue [American version], 1951 Dec (Box 289, Folder 2859)
        - Abridgement: "A Little Portrait of Colette, printed version [as "Colette"], Vogue [British version], 1954 Oct (Box 289, Folder 2860)
      - "Last Words of Colette", review of The Blue Lantern
        - Draft, typescript carbon, ca. 1963 (Box 290, Folder 2861)
        - Printed version [as "The Gods Have Green Eyes"], Book Week, 1963 Nov 24 (Box 290, Folder 2862)
      - "Short Novels of Colette"
        - Publicity and clippings, 1951-52 (Box 290, Folder 2863)
      - [Untitled]
        - Draft sections, holograph, typescript, and carbon, corrected (Box 290, Folder 2864-2871)
    - Colum, Padraic
      - "Introductory remarks before the performance of Padraic Colum's play", draft, holograph, corrected, 1953 (Box 290, Folder 2872)
    - Connolly, Cyril
      "A Famous Book Reviewer", review of Previous Convictions
      - Notebook, ca. 1963-65
      - Printed version, [as "Subjects before he predicates"], Book Week, 1964 Oct 4
    - Conrad, Joseph
      [Response to inquiry about Conrad]
      - Printed version, Wiadomosci, 1958 Aug 31
      - Printed version, Joseph Conrad: Centennial Essays, 1960 (Box 290, Folder 2875)
    - Cummings, E. E.
      - "Cummings: The Poet of Sentiment and Ribaldry" notebook, ca. 1962 (Box 291, Folder 2876)
    - Cunard, Maud, Lady
      See: Moore, George and Lady Maud Cunard,
      - Box 312, folder 3051
    - Cunninghame-Graham, R. B.
      - "A Historian of Conquests", review of Hernando de Soto, draft [copied], typescript carbon (Box 291, Folder 2877)
        Includes "A Note on Mr. Cunninghame-Graham"
    - Dinesen, Isak
      "Isak Dinesen, the Storyteller"
      - Notebook, ca. 1958-62
      - Excerpt, printed version, as "Isak Dinesen Tells a Tale", Harper's, 1960 Mar (Box 291, Folder 2879)